ARIN STURM

Portland, Oregon · (503) 489-9903 contact@organicmediadevelopment.com

As a professional with over 20 years of technology industry experience, I successfully design, develop, and maintain user interfaces for software applications. I enjoy logical problem-solving and using my analytical skills to take on complex challenges and find flexible, creative, and simple solutions. I am an independently motivated worker, dedicated to continuous learning, and persistent in improving computer user experiences.

EXPERIENCE

Senior UI Developer Blue Health Intelligence

February 2018 to January 2023

- Created UI tools to improve the user experience of accessing data by uploading and downloading reports generated on specific parameters.
- Developed customized extensions for integrated third-party systems to introduce advanced functionality to improve the user experience for navigation.
- Coordinated with client management to transition the existing products to a new UI theme with a custom stylesheet reusable for all the systems.
- Designed screenshot mockups of features for efficient product planning and created rapid prototypes for proof-of-concept technical system improvements.
- Proposed aggregation and validation of data to produce a dynamically generated form to help clients with scheduling reports.

UI Engineer Vant4ge

May 2015 to October 2017

 Designed assessments for criminal corrections and developed analytic reporting to reduce recidivism.

UI Developer

December 2014 to March 2015

Elsevier ExitCare

Designed and developed multiple website themes to update the patient care education system.

Application Developer Lightstorm Entertainment

October 2013 to November 2014

Developed custom tools for managing digital film resources to build the Avatar movie sequels.

Game Developer

July 2013 to October 2013

iSite Design

 Developed bubble shooter and matching games for the FIFA World Cup for Liberty Mutual's intranet.

UI Developer

April 2012 to June 2013

PGi

 Created event messaging and user feedback for the iMeet Live software to support interactive events.

Video Player Developer PBS

June 2009 to March 2012

• Developed and maintained custom features in multiple video players for national TV channel distribution.

Education

Bachelor of Arts in Multimedia University of Advancing Technology December 2003

PMI Agile Certified Practitioner Exam Course Learn Smart July 2018

JavaScript Advanced Security Training Secure Code Warrior August 2021

Technical Experience

- Data sources AWS, Cookies, JSON, Local Storage, MongoDB, MySQL, REST, Shared Object, SQL, Web Sockets, XML
- Frameworks Ajax, Angular, AngularJS, Bootstrap, Django, Enigma.JS, Jasmine, JQuery, MXML, Node.JS, OSMF, React
- Languages ActionScript, ASP, ASP.NET, CSS, HTML/5, Java, JavaScript, PHP, Python, TypeScript, UML, Visual Basic
- Operating Systems Windows, Mac OS, Linux
- Project Management Adobe, Asana, BaseCamp, Confluence, Google, Jira, Microsoft Office Suite, Outlook
- **Software** Eclipse, Figma, Flash, Gimp, Lotus Notes, Notepad++, Photoshop, Sketch, Sublime, Visual Studio, Web Storm, Zeplin
- Team Communication Google Meet, GoTo Meeting, HipChat, Skype, Slack, Teams, WebEx, Zoom
- Tools Ant, Auth0, Bamboo, Brightcove, Chart.JS, ConnectReport, CruiseControl, D3, Gulp, Jenkins, Karma, Material UI, MaterializeCSS, Maven, OAS Ad Server, Oauth, Qlik Sense, ReportManager, Selenium, Tableau, TeamCity, thePlatform, Visio, WordPress
- Version Control Bitbucket, GIT, GitHub, SVN, Team Foundation Server, Visual Studio Online

Activities

In my spare time, I enjoy playing board games with friends and family. As a pet project during the pandemic, I adapted Battleship and Bingo into a single customized game application that hosts multiple players and a scoreboard UI.